Guide to the John White Geary Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Moore, W. W. Letter to Geary. February 11, 1857. 1 p.
Morrison, J. Letter to Governor Wright. November 12, 1856. With postscript by N. Hayden. 2 pp.
Murphy, William E. Letter to Geary. January 21, 1857. 1 p.
Nichols, Julia A. Letter to Geary. November 21, 1856. 3 pp.
Nichols, R. D. Letter to Geary. February 26, 1857. 1 p.
Nones, J. H. Letter to C. S. Haldeman. April 8, 1857. 2 pp.
[Nute, Ephraim.] Statement of treatment received from the "Border Ruffians" on August 28, 1856, when he was traveling with his sister-in-law, whose husband, William C. Hoppe, had been murdered a few days before. September 15, 1857. Unsigned. 5 pp.
O'Hern, M. P. Two telegrams and a letter to Geary. July 23- August 27, 1856. 3 pp.
Orr, John M. Letter to Geary. August 19, 1856. 1 p.
Ottawa Creek, K. T. Proceedings of a meeting at Otaway [ sic ] Creek, February 14, 1857, S. Mewhinney, chairman, John W. Griffith, secretary. Copy. 1 p.
Paine, Alfred J. et al. vs. Territory of Kansas. Copy of the judgment rendered, certified February 17, 1857, James R. Whitehead, clerk, by W. L. Kuykendall, deputy clerk, 2 pp.
Painter, C. R. Letter to Geary. January 15, 1857. 1 p.
Painter, Israel. Invitation to a dinner in Pittsburgh. March 19, 1857. Signed by Israel Painter, P. C. Shannon and 18 other citizens. 3 pp.
Pardee, A. W. Two letters to Geary. January 28, February 3, 1857. 5 pp.
Parrott, Marcus J. Two letters to Geary. September 13, October 5, 1856. 2 pp.
Parsons, Theophilus. Letter to Geary, introducing John Coffey Douglass, Yale 1853. October 29, 1856. 1 p.
Partridge, William. Letter to Geary. January 24, 1857. 3 pp.
Patrick, Albert G. Letter to Geary. December 2, 1856. 2 pp.
Patterson, Almis B. Letter to Geary. October 30, 1856. 3 pp
. Patterson, Findley. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.
Paynter, Reece. Letter to Geary. February 20, 1857. 1 p.
Peck, John. Two letters to Geary. October 24, 1856, January 30, 1857. 4 pp.
Pellit, Sarah. Two letters to Geary. January 15, 1856 [i.e., 1857], February 3, 1857. 5 pp.
Peterson, T. B. Letter to John H. Gihon. January 5, 1857. 2 pp.
Petition to Governor Geary to pardon Elias Roark. November 24, 1856. With 101 signatures. 4 pp.
Phillips, E. A. Letter to Geary. November 8, 1856. 2 pp.
Pierce, Franklin. Telegram and letter to Geary. August 26, 1856, March 25, [1857]. 2 pp.
Pleasant Grove, Ind., Citizens. Petition to Governor Joseph A. Wright in behalf of William Updegraff. October 27, 1857. With 42 signatures. 2 pp.
Plumley, George R. Two letters to Geary. January 14, March 2, 1857. 2 pp.
Pomeroy, Phinehas. Letter to Geary. February 2, 1857. 1 p.
Pomeroy, Samuel Clarke. Letter to Geary. February 10, 1857. 1 p.
Porter, David R. Letter to Geary. August 1, 1856. 1 p.
Price, Thomas B. Two letters to Geary. August 28, 1856, July 1857. 5 pp.
Price, William. Letter to Geary. November 5, 1856. 3 pp.
Prisoners at Lecompton, November 12, 1856. a list. 4 pp.
Purse, William A. Two letters to Geary. May 19, 1856, February 20, 1857. 3 pp.
Rainey, William. Letter to Geary. November 17, 1856. 2 pp.
Ray, Alexander. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. 1 p.
Reeder, Andrew H. Letter to Geary. May 19, 1857. 2 pp.
Republican Central Committee of the City and County of New York. Resolution adopted March 25, 1857. Signed by John A. Kennedy, president, William Peel, J. L. Woodford, secretaries. Copy. 1 p.
Reynolds, L. C. Letter to Geary. October 26, 1856. 1 p.
Rice, John T. Affidavit. Leavenworth Co., K. T. January 8, 1857, about the sacking of the post office at Alexandria, September 1856, Jos. L. McAleer, postmaster. Sworn before Richard R. Rees, with a note signed by Lewis N. Reis, postmaster, Leavenworth City. 1 p.
Richardson, William P. Letter to Nathaniel Pascall. February 10, 1857. Copy. 3 pp.
Richmond, L. Three letters to Geary. October 18-November 28, 1856. 8 pp.
Ritchey, A. J. Letter to Geary. September 27, 1856. 1 p.
Roark, Elias vs. Territory of Kansas. Copy of judgment, certified February 16, 1857 by James R. Whitehead, clerk, W. L. Kuykendall, deputy. 2 pp.
Roberts, William G. Letter to Geary. November 5, 1856. 2 pp.
Roberts, William Young. Two letters to Geary of same date. February 1, 1857. 3 pp.
Robinson, Charles. Four letters to Geary. September 14-December 20, 1856. 7 pp.
---- Letter to Geary about the postmaster at Lawrence. December 26, 1856. With added notes, December 27, by G. W. Brown, S. B. Prentiss and C. W. Babcock. 4 pp.
Rodgers, George J[?]. Letter to Geary. September 27, 1856. 2 pp.
Rodrigue, Aristides. Letter to Geary. February 4, 1857. 1 p.
---- Agreement, March 9, 1856, canceling contract of December 27, 1855, for building the capitol. Witnessed by John H. Gihon. 1 p.
---- Statement of settlement. March 9, 1857. 1 p.
---- Abstract of settlement of capitol building contract with Rodrigue. [April 16, 1857.] Copy. 1 p.
Rogers, A. A. Letter to Geary. September 30, 1856. 1 p.
Ross, Randal. Letter to Geary. January 20, 1857. 2 pp.
Rowe, George J. Letter to Geary. January 14, 1857. Signed also by Jacob Rowe. 2 pp.
Ruff, B. F. Letter to Geary. November 21, 1856. 1 p.
Rumbold, William. Two letters to Geary. September 15, 1856, March 14, 1857. 2 pp.
Russell, William Hepburn. Seven letters and a telegram to Geary. December 1, 1856-February 16, 1857. 13 pp.
Sansom, J. B. Two letters to Geary. January 12, March 16, 1857. 5 pp.
Scamman, T. Letter to Geary. January 10, 1857. 1 p.
Schley, James M. Letter to Geary. August 18, 1856. 1 p.
Seegar, John R. L. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.
Settle, William H. Letter to Geary. December 1, 1856. 1 p.
Sexton, Charles A. Letter to Geary. November 13, 1856. 1 p.
Shearer, Crawford W. Letter to Geary. August 7, 1856. 1 p.
Sherrard, William T. Letter to Geary. December 22, 1856. 2 pp.
---- Territory of Kansas vs. William T. Sherrard. Writ of arrest, signed by S. G. Cato, assistant justice of the Supreme Court, K. T., February 9, 1857. 2 pp.
Shore, S. T. Letter to Geary. November 5, 1856. 4 pp.
Sibley, Henry Hastings. Two letters to Geary. December 5, 1856, January 12, 1857. 7 pp.
Smith, Hamilton. Letter to Geary. December 30, 1856. 2 pp.
Smith, Persifor Frazer. Nine letters to Geary. September 16, 1856- February 16, 1857. 28 pp.
Smith, Samuel O. Letter to Geary. September 16, 1856. 1 p.
Sons of Temperance. Friendship Division No. 19. Resolution of thanks to Governor Geary, April 5, 1870. Signed by Oliver Martin and A. G. Little. Broadside. 36 x 47 1/2 cm.
Speer, W. R. Letter to Geary. September 16, 1857. 2 pp.
Spencer, John C. Letter to Geary. January 1, 1857. 1 p.
Spencer, William. Letter to Geary. January 17, 1857. 2 pp.
Spering, Joshua. Letter to Geary. January 5, 1857. 2 pp.
Spicer, John. Letter to Geary. Unsigned and undated. Endorsed: "Private. John Spicer, Decr. 21st, 1856." 2 pp.
Squatter Sovereign, Atchison, K. T. Bill for printing proclamations and advertisement for proposals for building the capitol, February 9, 1857. Receipted by Stringfellow, Kelly & Lasey, and certified February 21, 1857, by Wilson Shannon. Duplicate. 1 p.
Sterett, Samuel H. Letter to Geary. September 12, 1856. 4 pp.
Sterett, William A. Letter to Geary. September 29, 1856. 3 pp.
Stevens, William. Letter to Geary. March 21, 1857. 2 pp.
Stewart, Charles. Letter to Geary. August 7, 1856. Written and signed by B. K. Johnston. 1 p.
Stewart, Owen C. Letter to Geary. February 18, 1857. 1 p.
Stewart, Samuel. Letter to Geary. November 15, 1856. 2 pp.
Stewart, T. G. Letter to Geary. January 27, 1857. 2 pp.
Stillman, E. A. Letter to Geary. December 25, 1856. 2 pp.
Storrs, N. S. Letter to Geary. February 20, 1857. 2 pp.
Strickler, Hiram Jackson. Two letters to Geary. May 11, August 11, 1857. 3 pp.
Strong, D. Letter to Geary. July 30, 1856. 3 pp.
Stroud, R. P. Letter to Geary. July 31, 1856. 2 pp.
Stump, John M. Two letters to Geary. August 20, November 12, 1856. 2 pp.
Sturgeon, Isaac H. Three letters to Geary. September 9, 1856- January 29, 1857. 3 pp.
---- Letter to Wilson Shannon. January 27, 1857. Signed by J. W. Wills. 1 p.
Swift, A. C. Letter to Geary. January 18, 1857. 1 p.
Swiss Colonization Society, Cincinnati. Two letters to Geary. January 19, 1857, signed by J. C. Christian and Felix Schelling; March 7, 1857, signed by Felix Schelling. 6 pp.
Tanner, William. Letter to Geary. February 22, 1857. 1 p.
Tassey, Mrs. Emily E. Letter to Geary. January 12, 1857. 2 pp.
Tebbs, A. Sidney. Three letters to Geary. August 4, 1856- March 19, 1857. 7 pp.
Ten Eyck, Anthony. Two letters to Geary. November 7, December 12, 1856. 7 pp.
Thomas, Charles H. Letter to Geary. January 12, 1857. 1 p.
Thomas, Francis John. Letter to Geary. January 20, 1857. 3 pp.
Thomas, Lewis A. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 4 pp.
Titus, Henry T. Letter to Geary. November 8, 1856. 1 p.
---- Statement regarding the attack on him sworn to before R. B. Nelson, J. P. August 25, 1856. 1 p.
Todd, J. M. Letter to Geary. August 3, 1856. 2 pp.
Topeka, Ladies of. Petition for the pardon and release of Free State prisoners. [October? 1856.] With 19 signatures. 1 p.
Totten, Thomas. Complaint to Governor Geary against Partridge and Holmes. February 25, 1857. Signed also by Henry Tuley, A. H. McFadin, H. W. Peck and Baptis Peora. 2 pp.
Upton, John. Letter to Geary [?]. August 7, 1856. With postscript by S. F. Tappan. 2 pp.
Van Nostrand, A. M. Letter to Geary. January 14, 1857. 3 pp.
Wattles, Augustus. Letter to Geary. January 25, 1857. 1 p.
Wea Emigrants. Address to Governor Geary. Wea Plains, Ind., [1857]. Signed by Daniel H. Roberts, John O. Wattles, Milton Hollingsworth. 4 pp.
---- Constitution and list of members. [n.d.] 5 pp.
Whitfield, John W. Letter to Geary. January 18, 1857. 3 pp.
Whittlesey, Elisha. 15 letters to Geary. October 23, 1856- April 25, 1857. Signatures only. 30 pp. Enclosed with the letter of January 28, 1857 are a statment of differences in the account of Governor Shannon; copy of a letter from Whittlesey to Shannon, January 27, 1857; and two copies of Owen C. Stewart's bill for services on the capitol building, certified, January 23, 1857, by Wilson Shannon. 8 pp.
Williams, Lorange D. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 1 p.
---- Affidavit before A. H. McFadin about the death of Henry Sherman. March 3, 1857. 1 p.
Williams, William. Letter to Geary. August 27, 1856. 2 pp.
Wilson, George. Letter to Colonel Boone. March 3, 1857. Signed also by Thomas Totten, and forwarded by Boone to Geary. 2 pp.
Wilson, John A. Letter to Geary. November 4, 1856. 1 p.
Winston, J. Letter to Geary. February 10, [1857]. 1 p.
Winston, Thomas B. Letter to Geary. January 21, 1857. 1 p.
Wise, Henry Alexander. Requisition to Governor Geary for delivery of Joseph L. McCubbin. January 3, 1857. Signed by Henry A. Wise, Governor, and George W. Munford, Secretary, with the seal of the state of Virginia. Accompanied by Governor Wise's appointment of Charles P. Arnold as agent to demand and receive Joseph L. McCubbin, signed by Governor Wise and Secretary Munford, January 3, 1857; and statement of Charles P. Arnold before Thomas S. Wood, December 29, 1856. 4 pp.
Womack, George W. Letter to Geary. March 9, 1857. 4 pp.
---- Letter to "Tommy." January 15, 1857. 4 pp.
Woodbridge, F. H. Letter to Geary. January 3, 1857. 1 p.
Woodruff, W. D. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. 2 pp.
Woods, Samuel. Letter to Geary. February 15, 1857. 2 pp.
Wright, Joseph Albert. Letter to Geary. November 11, 1856. Signature only. 1 p.
Wright, W. W. Letter to Geary. February 19, 1857. 1 p.
Zigler, I. Telegram and letter to Geary. August 8, September 8, 1856. 2 pp.
Kansas -- History -- 1854-1861; Kansas -- Politics and government -- 1854-1861; Legal instruments -- United States; Petitions -- United State; Public officers -- Kansas; Brown, George Washington, 1827-1906; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866; Cooke, Philip St. George, 1809-1895; Geary, Edward R., II.; Geary, Edward R., 1811-1886; Geary, John White, 1819-1873; Gihon, John H.; Haldeman, Cyrus S.; Jones, Andrew J.; McAllister, Richard; McCaslin, Maxwell; Russell, William Hepburn, 1812-1872; Whittlesey, Elisha, 1783-1863; Kansas Territory. Governor (1856-1857: Geary)
- Correspondence, 1862-1871; Series I; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, consists primarily of the official correspondence of John White Geary, Governor of Kansas Territory, 1856-57, and includes both letters to and from Geary. The letters from Governor Geary are copies, usually in his secretary's hand. The series also contains a few personal and family papers. The correspondence, with the exception of five letters written between 1862 and 1871, is dated from April 22, 1856, to December 4, 1857
  - Correspondence, 1856 Apr-Jul (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Aug 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Aug 16-30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Sep 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Sep 11-16 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Sep 17-30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Oct 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Oct 16-26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Oct 27-31 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Nov 1-7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Nov 8-14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Nov 14-30 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Dec 1-8 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1856 Dec 9-31 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Jan 1-9 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Jan 10-18 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Jan 19-27 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Jan 28-31 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Feb 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Feb 11-17 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Feb 18-28 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Mar 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Mar 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Apr (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1857 May-Jun (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1857 Jul-Dec (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Notes on Kansas, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1856-57 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1862-71 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Family correspondence, 1855-57 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Private Letter Book and Executive Minutes, 1856-1857; Series II; 0.6; (3 volumes)
  Series II, Private Letter Book and Executive Minutes, consists of three bound volumes kept by Governor Geary's private secretary, John H. Gihon. In two volumes, labelled Executive Minutes, Gihon copied offical letters to and from the governor, his messages to the legislature, other official acts, and a chronological record of events. A third, unlabelled volume contains copies of Geary's letters and reports to various federal officials, including Presidents Pierce and Buchanan
  - Executive minutes and official correspondence, 1856-57 (Box 3, Folder Vol. 1)
  - Executive minutes and official correspondence, 1857 Feb-Mar (Box 3, Folder Vol. 2)
  - Official correspondence (entitled "Governor Geary's Private Diary, kept by his Secretary"), 1856-57 (Box 3, Folder Vol. 3)
- Transcript, 1856-1857; Series III; 0.2; (1 volume)
  Series III, Transcript, consists of a typewritten transcript of some of the more important papers in the collection. The transcript is in a single volume
  - Transcript: "A collection of autograph letters and documents written to and by John White Geary during his governorship of Kansas Territory", 1856-57 (Box 4)